<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>apache on Mike Ball</title><link>http://mikeball.info/tags/apache/</link><description>Recent content in apache on Mike Ball</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://mikeball.info/tags/apache/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apache Persistent Connection Problems</title><link>http://mikeball.info/blog/apache-persistent-connection-problems/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mikeball.info/blog/apache-persistent-connection-problems/</guid><description>Problem: Apache worker thread pool is exhausted; server CPU consumption is high.
Solution: reduce the Apache KeepAliveTimeout from its 15 second default (disclaimer: maybe, depending on circumstances).
Background HTTP keep-alive functionality seeks to improve efficiency. In effect, HTTP keep-alive — also referred to as HTTP persistent connection and HTTP connection reuse allows the use of a single TCP connection to send and receive multiple HTTP requests and responses.
Keep-alive reduces the latency associated with opening a new TCP connection for each HTTP request.</description></item><item><title>Secure Session Cookie in Rails over HTTPS</title><link>http://mikeball.info/blog/secure-session-cookie-in-rails-over-https/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mikeball.info/blog/secure-session-cookie-in-rails-over-https/</guid><description>The secure flag can be set by an application server when sending a cookie within an HTTP response. By setting the secure flag, an HTTP client — such as a web browser — prevents cookie transmission unless the response is securely encrypted over HTTPS.
However, many web applications redirect http:// to https://, and many Ruby on Rails applications are fronted by a web server such as Ngnix or Apache. Often, HTTPS is terminated at the Nginx/Apache layer.</description></item></channel></rss>