<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on Mike Ball</title><link>/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on Mike Ball</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>31 West Philly Illustrations</title><link>/projects/31-west-philly-illustrations/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/31-west-philly-illustrations/</guid><description>For Artclash’s 2017 West Philadelphia Fun-a-Day show, I drew 31 West Philadelphia-inspired illustrations, one each day through the month of January.</description></item><item><title>Hopscotch Coffee Illustration</title><link>/projects/hopscotch-coffee-illustration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/hopscotch-coffee-illustration/</guid><description>18&amp;quot; x 24&amp;quot; micron pen drawing for Hopscotch Coffee&amp;rsquo;s Bloomington, IN shop.</description></item><item><title>TimesGrapher</title><link>/projects/timesgrapher/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/timesgrapher/</guid><description>TimesGrapher seeks to shed light on what topics are covered by the New York Times from year-to-year. The simple application leverages the New York Times API to visualize the differences in coverage offered to any two topics in any year between 1981 and 2013, in effect providing insight on the year-to-year relevancy of current events, as well as arguable editorial bias.
The application is built with Rails and Backbone.js.
TimesGrapher was built as a hobby project; it is not affiliated with the New York Times.</description></item><item><title>wp2middleman</title><link>/projects/wp2middleman/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/wp2middleman/</guid><description>wp2middleman is a Ruby gem that migrates the Wordpress posts in a Wordpress XML export file to middleman-style markdown files.
wp2middleman provides a wp2mm commandline executable, as well as a WP2Middleman module.
View source and documentation on Github »</description></item><item><title>31 Dream Homes</title><link>/projects/31-dream-homes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/31-dream-homes/</guid><description>For Artclash’s 2012 West Philadelphia Fun-a-Day show, I drew 31 dream homes, one each day through the month of January.</description></item><item><title>Lobber</title><link>/projects/lobber/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/lobber/</guid><description>Lobber is a simple command line utility used to quickly upload a directory to Amazon S3.
Lobber is built with Ruby and can be downloaded from Rubygems.
View its source code on GitHub »</description></item><item><title>Philadelphia Police Advisory Commission Complaint Map</title><link>/projects/philadelphia-police-advisory-commission-complaint-map/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/philadelphia-police-advisory-commission-complaint-map/</guid><description>My map of 2009 – 2012 complaints filed with the Philadelphia Police Advisory Commission won first place at the 2013 Barcamp News Innovation Hackathon.
The map plots the details surrounding complaints filed with the Police Advisory Commission by citizens against Philadelphia Police Officers. Its data is published by Open Data Philly and has been imported to a public Google Spreadsheet. According to Open Data Philly, the data comes directly from the Police Advisory Commission Complaint Database.</description></item><item><title>Gull</title><link>/projects/gull/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/gull/</guid><description>A set of images for use by Nate Rappole as a postcard series.</description></item><item><title>TEDxPhilly</title><link>/projects/tedxphilly/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/tedxphilly/</guid><description>The organizers of TEDxPhilly contacted me to create a seam-less, infinitely tiling illustration to be used as a background image throughout the conference’s web collateral. The illustration is type-based and inspired by “the city,” the 2011 conference theme.</description></item><item><title>Our Philadelphia</title><link>/projects/our-philadelphia/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/our-philadelphia/</guid><description>I partnered with Gabriel Farrell and Cecily Anderson to design and build ourphiladelphia.org for Common Cause, a nonprofit, nonpartisan citizen’s lobbying organization working to promote open, honest, and accountable government.
Our Philadelphia is a community website designed to provide information to Philadelphians about the role of money in local politics. The site features an address-based representative search tool, a news publishing platform, RSS feeds, user accounts and profiles, as well as an extensive database of local campaign donor information.</description></item><item><title>Battles</title><link>/projects/battles/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/battles/</guid><description>Battles: Sea and Land are two illustration-based narrative zines made in the Summer of 2006.</description></item><item><title>Brainworms</title><link>/projects/brainworms/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/brainworms/</guid><description>T-shirt design.</description></item><item><title>Clap Yr Hands</title><link>/projects/clap-yr-hands/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/clap-yr-hands/</guid><description>Clap Yr Hands is a zine I occasionally publish, usually featuring illustration and collage.</description></item><item><title>free103point9</title><link>/projects/free103point9/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/free103point9/</guid><description>Gabe Farrell and I developed this site for the New York-based transmission arts advocacy organization free103point9.
The site is built on Django. In addition to brochuring free103point9, the site also serves as a transmission arts digital archive, hosts an event calendar, and houses free103′s online radio station.</description></item><item><title>Taylor &amp; Juliette</title><link>/projects/taylor-juliette/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/taylor-juliette/</guid><description>I created a simple brochure website and letter-pressed invite for Taylor &amp;amp; Juliette&amp;rsquo;s wedding. The website and invite feature original illustrations, as well as a hand-drawn typeface created for the wedding materials.</description></item><item><title>Anthroapology</title><link>/projects/anthroapology/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/anthroapology/</guid><description>This quarter-size zine is a collection of illustrations I made while living and teaching English in Bangkok, Thailand in 2005/2006.</description></item><item><title>Polaroid Celluloid</title><link>/projects/polaroid-celluloid/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/polaroid-celluloid/</guid><description>Hand drawn illustration for the zine Polaroid Celluloid.</description></item><item><title>31 Portraits</title><link>/projects/31-portraits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/31-portraits/</guid><description>For Artclash’s 2010 Fun-a-Day show, I drew 31 portraits, one for each day of the month of January. The illustrations were compiled in Anthrotopography, a small, photocopied zine.</description></item><item><title>31 Patterns</title><link>/projects/31-patterns/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/31-patterns/</guid><description>Nate Johnson, Kara Schlindwein, and I collaborated on this book of 31 illustrated patterns for Artclash’s annual Fun-A-Day art show. We created one pattern each day throughout the month of January 2009 and compiled our finished work in a handmade book. The patterns are designed to tile infinitely.</description></item><item><title>Parcell Press</title><link>/projects/parcell-press/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/parcell-press/</guid><description>I designed and developed the logo, identity, and ecommerce website for Parcell Press, an independent zine, art, and book distributor.</description></item><item><title>Muscle Crap</title><link>/projects/muscle-crap/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/muscle-crap/</guid><description>A few of my illustrations were featured in Muscle Crap, a limited edition artists&amp;rsquo; book published by Salt Tooth Press in 2004.</description></item></channel></rss>