<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Backbone on Mike Ball</title><link>/tags/backbone/</link><description>Recent content in Backbone on Mike Ball</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/backbone/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>TimesGrapher</title><link>/projects/timesgrapher/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/timesgrapher/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;TimesGrapher seeks to shed light on what topics are covered by the New York Times from year-to-year. The simple application leverages the &lt;a href="http://developer.nytimes.com/docs"&gt;New York Times API&lt;/a&gt; to visualize the differences in coverage offered to any two topics in any year between 1981 and 2013, in effect providing insight on the year-to-year relevancy of current events, as well as arguable editorial bias.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application is built with &lt;a href="http://rubyonrails.org"&gt;Rails&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://backbonejs.org"&gt;Backbone.js&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TimesGrapher was built as a hobby project; it is not affiliated with the New York Times.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Philadelphia Police Advisory Commission Complaint Map</title><link>/projects/philadelphia-police-advisory-commission-complaint-map/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/philadelphia-police-advisory-commission-complaint-map/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;My map of 2009 – 2012 complaints filed with the Philadelphia Police Advisory Commission won first place at the 2013 Barcamp News Innovation Hackathon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The map plots the details surrounding complaints filed with the Police Advisory Commission by citizens against Philadelphia Police Officers. Its data is published by &lt;a href="http://www.opendataphilly.org/opendata/resource/218/philadelphia-police-advisory-commission-complaints"&gt;Open Data Philly&lt;/a&gt; and has been imported to a public &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheet/ccc?key=0Aii0ITjxvJ6fdFlPNHVINHY2dVhfODNsY2JWU0U0NHc&amp;amp;usp=sharing#gid=0"&gt;Google Spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt;. According to Open Data Philly, the data comes directly from the Police Advisory Commission Complaint Database.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>