<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>terraform on Mike Ball</title><link>/tags/terraform/</link><description>Recent content in terraform on Mike Ball</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/terraform/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Advanced Terraform Logic</title><link>/blog/advanced-terraform-logic/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/advanced-terraform-logic/</guid><description>Critics argue Terraform is limiting and doesn&amp;rsquo;t adequately enable the expression of complex logic in HCL. While imperfect, Terraform does indeed often accommodate complex logic. As a reference example, the following illustrates how Terraform constructs such as for_each, for/in, if, try, various functions, and custom local data structures can be used to successfully satisfy a relatively logic-intensive use case.
github.com/mdb/terraform-advanced-logic-demo homes the source code referenced throughout this post.
Problem For example&amp;rsquo;s sake, imagine a contrived scenario:</description></item><item><title>Terraform Provider Development Demystified</title><link>/blog/terraform-provider-development-demystified/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/terraform-provider-development-demystified/</guid><description>Many Terraform practitioners may be unfamiliar with provider development. How are providers actually implemented? The following offers an outline of a brief presentation I gave to the HBO Max Strategic Global Infrastructure team.
Review of the basics First, let&amp;rsquo;s establish a foundation, especially for those who may be less familiar with Terraform.
Terraform fundamentals Terraform enables users to describe infrastructure resources &amp;ndash; and their dependency relationships &amp;ndash; in .tf files using HCL, and to automate the creation and ongoing management of that infrastructure via the Terraform command line inferface.</description></item><item><title>Transforming Terraform Output Values to Markdown with Terraputs</title><link>/blog/transforming-terraform-output-values-to-markdown-with-terraputs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/transforming-terraform-output-values-to-markdown-with-terraputs/</guid><description>An introduction to using a tool I wrote, terraputs, to transform Terraform configuration output values to markdown. I owe a hat tip to my colleagues Justin LaRose and Travis Truman for giving me the idea to create terraputs.
Problem You&amp;rsquo;d like to publish your Terraform configuration&amp;rsquo;s up-to-date output values in a human-friendly, easy-to-read, accessible format. Perhaps you&amp;rsquo;d like to publish their current values to your project&amp;rsquo;s README.md, a wiki, or some other form of documentation.</description></item><item><title>Terraform Plan Validation With Open Policy Agent</title><link>/blog/terraform-plan-validation-with-open-policy-agent/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/terraform-plan-validation-with-open-policy-agent/</guid><description>A pattern for automating Terraform plan analysis using Open Policy Agent.
Problem Your project&amp;rsquo;s CI/CD pipeline performs a Terraform plan prior to executing a Terraform apply. The CI/CD pipeline gates on the Terraform plan, such that team members can manually review its output for unwanted, problematic, and/or destructive resource modifications. While the manual plan review helps protect against the application of changes that could negatively impact systems&amp;rsquo; availability, the analysis is tedious and error prone.</description></item><item><title>Using Terraform workspaces</title><link>/blog/using-terraform-workspaces/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/using-terraform-workspaces/</guid><description>Problem: In distributed software engineering, it&amp;rsquo;s common to maintain multiple named environments, each of which is a distinct, logical grouping of infrastructure resources. For example, utilizing separate production and pre-production environments (staging, development, etc.) is a traditional multi-tiered environment strategy in structuring a phased software build, test, and release lifecycle (or even a phased approach in deploying the software infrastructure itself). But how can a single Terraform configuration be used to safely manage infrastructure resources spanning multiple parallel environments?</description></item></channel></rss>