<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Journalism on Mike Ball</title><link>/tags/journalism/</link><description>Recent content in Journalism on Mike Ball</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/journalism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>TimesGrapher</title><link>/projects/timesgrapher/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/timesgrapher/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;TimesGrapher seeks to shed light on what topics are covered by the New York Times from year-to-year. The simple application leverages the &lt;a href="http://developer.nytimes.com/docs"&gt;New York Times API&lt;/a&gt; to visualize the differences in coverage offered to any two topics in any year between 1981 and 2013, in effect providing insight on the year-to-year relevancy of current events, as well as arguable editorial bias.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application is built with &lt;a href="http://rubyonrails.org"&gt;Rails&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://backbonejs.org"&gt;Backbone.js&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TimesGrapher was built as a hobby project; it is not affiliated with the New York Times.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Nicar 2013 Conference</title><link>/blog/nicar-2013-conference/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/nicar-2013-conference/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;On February 27 – March 2, I attended NICAR 2013 in Louisville, Kentucky. My attendance was generously funded through a Temple University Center for Public Interest Journalism sponsorship.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-is-nicar"&gt;What is NICAR?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NICAR is the National Institute for Computer-Assisted Reporting, a program of Investigative Reporters and Editors, Inc. and the Missouri School of Journalism. In the institute’s &lt;a href="http://www.ire.org/nicar/about/"&gt;own words&lt;/a&gt;, “NICAR has trained thousands of journalists in the practical skills of finding, prying loose and analyzing electronic information.” Data discovery, data analysis, and news applications such as interactive maps and info-graphics offer common examples of the “CAR” in “NICAR.” Nate Silver’s &lt;a href="http://fivethirtyeight.blogs.nytimes.com/"&gt;FiveThirtyEight blog&lt;/a&gt; and its suite of analyses, maps, graphics, and interactive applications is another popular example. In the world of of quality public interest news — and the mission of helping people better understand its quantitative nuance — CAR boasts a potent mix of computer science, design, and journalism. Within this field, NICAR is the flagship conference.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>