<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Infrastructure on Mike Ball</title><link>/tags/infrastructure/</link><description>Recent content in Infrastructure on Mike Ball</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/infrastructure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Terraform Provider Development Demystified</title><link>/blog/terraform-provider-development-demystified/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/terraform-provider-development-demystified/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Many Terraform practitioners may be unfamiliar with &lt;a href="https://www.terraform.io/language/providers"&gt;provider&lt;/a&gt; development. How are providers actually implemented? The following offers an outline of a brief presentation I gave to the &lt;a href="https://www.hbomax.com/"&gt;HBO Max&lt;/a&gt; Strategic Global Infrastructure team.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="review-of-the-basics"&gt;Review of the basics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, let&amp;rsquo;s establish a foundation, especially for those who may be less familiar with &lt;a href="https://www.terraform.io/"&gt;Terraform&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="terraform-fundamentals"&gt;Terraform fundamentals&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Terraform enables users to describe infrastructure resources &amp;ndash; and their dependency relationships &amp;ndash; in &lt;code&gt;.tf&lt;/code&gt; files using &lt;a href="https://github.com/hashicorp/hcl"&gt;HCL&lt;/a&gt;, and to automate the creation and ongoing management of that infrastructure via the Terraform command line interface.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Using Terraform workspaces</title><link>/blog/using-terraform-workspaces/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/using-terraform-workspaces/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem&lt;/strong&gt;: In distributed software engineering, it&amp;rsquo;s common to maintain multiple named &lt;em&gt;environments&lt;/em&gt;, each of which is a distinct, logical grouping of infrastructure resources. For example, utilizing separate &lt;code&gt;production&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;pre-production&lt;/code&gt; environments (&lt;code&gt;staging&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;development&lt;/code&gt;, etc.) is a traditional multi-tiered environment strategy in structuring a phased software build, test, and release lifecycle (or even a phased approach in deploying the software &lt;em&gt;infrastructure&lt;/em&gt; itself).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how can a single &lt;a href="https://terraform.io"&gt;Terraform&lt;/a&gt; configuration be used to safely manage infrastructure resources spanning multiple parallel environments? What are techniques for adequately isolating Terraform actions against one environment such that other environments aren&amp;rsquo;t inadvertently modified? How might the traditional, somewhat coarse-grained multi-tiered environment structure present Terraform management challenges in some circumstances?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>