<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Django on Mike Ball</title><link>/tags/django/</link><description>Recent content in Django on Mike Ball</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/django/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using South on a Heroku-hosted Django Project</title><link>/blog/using-south-on-a-heroku-hosted-django-project/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/using-south-on-a-heroku-hosted-django-project/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem&lt;/strong&gt;: You need to add new fields to the admin of a Django project hosted on Heroku but don&amp;rsquo;t want to destroy data by running &lt;code&gt;syncdb&lt;/code&gt; on your Heroku-hosted database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href="http://south.aeracode.org/docs/about.html"&gt;South&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These instructions assume you&amp;rsquo;re working in a clean checkout of a Heroku project named &lt;code&gt;heroku_project&lt;/code&gt;, which contains a Django project named &lt;code&gt;django_project&lt;/code&gt;, which contains an app named &lt;code&gt;django_app&lt;/code&gt;. You need to add a new admin field to &lt;code&gt;django_app&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open &lt;code&gt;settings.py&lt;/code&gt; and add &amp;lsquo;south&amp;rsquo; to your list of &lt;code&gt;INSTALLED_APPS&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Our Philadelphia</title><link>/projects/our-philadelphia/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/our-philadelphia/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I partnered with Gabriel Farrell and Cecily Anderson to design and build &lt;a href="http://ourphiladelphia.org"&gt;ourphiladelphia.org&lt;/a&gt; for Common Cause, a nonprofit, nonpartisan citizen’s lobbying organization working to promote open, honest, and accountable government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Philadelphia is a community website designed to provide information to Philadelphians about the role of money in local politics. The site features an address-based representative search tool, a news publishing platform, RSS feeds, user accounts and profiles, as well as an extensive database of local campaign donor information. The project was made possible by the Samuel S. Fels Fund.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>OurPhiladelphia.org Launched</title><link>/blog/ourphiladelphia.org-launched/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/ourphiladelphia.org-launched/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Last month, Gabriel Farrell, Cecily Anderson, and I launched &lt;a href="http://ourphiladelphia.org"&gt;OurPhiladelphia.org&lt;/a&gt; for our client, Common Cause, a nonprofit, nonpartisan citizen’s lobbying organization working to promote open, honest, and accountable government. While we plan to enhance and grow its functionality in the future, we hope this initial iteration of the site proves useful in helping Philadelphians access information about local politics. Our goal is to help create an open, honest, and accountable local government that serves the public interest.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>free103point9</title><link>/projects/free103point9/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/free103point9/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://github.com/gsf"&gt;Gabe Farrell&lt;/a&gt; and I developed this site for the New York-based transmission arts advocacy organization free103point9.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The site is built on Django. In addition to brochuring free103point9, the site also serves as a transmission arts digital archive, hosts an event calendar, and houses free103′s online radio station.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>