<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>gh on Mike Ball</title><link>/tags/gh/</link><description>Recent content in gh on Mike Ball</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 13:35:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/gh/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using the gh-dash gh CLI Extension to Manage GitHub Notifications</title><link>/blog/using-the-gh-dash-gh-cli-extension-to-manage-github-notifications/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 13:35:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/using-the-gh-dash-gh-cli-extension-to-manage-github-notifications/</guid><description>Written towards the goal of sharing my own practice with new team members, the following offers an overview of how I use the gh-dash CLI extension to manage GitHub notifications and pull request discussion.
Problem At scale, staying abreast of GitHub code review requests, GitHub issues of note, and related discussions is challenging. The challenges are further compounded when working across multiple GitHub organizations on both open and closed source projects, and especially when working as a member of multiple GitHub teams within one or more organizations.</description></item><item><title>Querying GitHub Release Data With gh and jq</title><link>/blog/querying-github-release-data-with-gh-and-jq/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/querying-github-release-data-with-gh-and-jq/</guid><description>A demo of semi-advanced gh CLI and jq querying techniques.
Problem You&amp;rsquo;d like to list the latest patch release associated with each of the latest 5 minor versions of Grafana represented as a JSON array.
For example:
[&amp;#34;9.1.6&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;9.0.9&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;8.5.13&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;8.4.11&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;8.3.11&amp;#34;] Solution Leverage that&amp;hellip;
Grafana releases are published as GitHub releases The gh CLI supports an api command, enabling users to query GitHub API endpoints The GitHub API supports a list releases endpoint gh api supports a --jq flag, enabling the ability to invoke jq queries against GitHub API responses For example:</description></item></channel></rss>