<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Automation on Mike Ball</title><link>/tags/automation/</link><description>Recent content in Automation on Mike Ball</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/automation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Transforming Terraform Output Values to Markdown with Terraputs</title><link>/blog/transforming-terraform-output-values-to-markdown-with-terraputs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/transforming-terraform-output-values-to-markdown-with-terraputs/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;An introduction to using a tool I wrote, &lt;a href="https://github.com/mdb/terraputs"&gt;&lt;code&gt;terraputs&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, to transform Terraform configuration &lt;a href="https://www.terraform.io/docs/language/values/outputs.html"&gt;output values&lt;/a&gt; to markdown. I owe a hat tip to my colleagues &lt;a href="https://github.com/justinlarose"&gt;Justin LaRose&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://github.com/trumant"&gt;Travis Truman&lt;/a&gt; for giving me the idea to create &lt;code&gt;terraputs&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="problem"&gt;Problem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;d like to publish your &lt;a href="https://terraform.io"&gt;Terraform&lt;/a&gt; configuration&amp;rsquo;s up-to-date &lt;a href="https://www.terraform.io/docs/language/values/outputs.html"&gt;output values&lt;/a&gt; in a human-friendly, easy-to-read, accessible format. Perhaps you&amp;rsquo;d like to publish their current values to your project&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;README.md&lt;/code&gt;, a wiki, or some other form of documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="solution"&gt;Solution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/mdb/terraputs"&gt;terraputs&lt;/a&gt; is a minimal CLI tool I created to print Terraform output values as &lt;a href="https://www.markdownguide.org"&gt;markdown&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Creating a Windows Installer for a node-webkit App on Mac OS</title><link>/blog/creating-a-windows-installer-for-a-node-webkit-app-on-mac-os/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/creating-a-windows-installer-for-a-node-webkit-app-on-mac-os/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/rogerwang/node-webkit"&gt;node-webkit&lt;/a&gt; provides a powerful path through which Linux, Windows, and Mac OS desktop applications can be authored using HTML5 and Node.js web technologies. &lt;a href="https://github.com/mllrsohn/grunt-node-webkit-builder"&gt;grunt-node-webkit-builder&lt;/a&gt; offers a tool through which a node-webkit application can be compiled to distributable directories. But how can an automated build process bundle the MS Windows files in an application installer in a headless continuous integration environment, or from the command line?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://nsis.sourceforge.net/Main_Page"&gt;makensis&lt;/a&gt; provides a solution. The tool can be used on Linux, though this overview focuses on Mac OS.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Automating Product Availability Alerts</title><link>/blog/automating-product-availability-alerts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/automating-product-availability-alerts/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem&lt;/strong&gt;: I&amp;rsquo;m renovating my kitchen. The Ikea sink I want is currently unavailable but may be back in stock any day, though Ikea&amp;rsquo;s website requires its users to jump through some hoops in determining the sink&amp;rsquo;s availabilty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;/strong&gt;: I made a web service that monitors the Ikea website and sends me a text message if the sink is suddenly in stock again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strongs&gt;Tool chain&lt;/strong&gt;: Rake, Capybara, Poltergeist, Sinatra, Twilio, and Heroku.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Automated Tests: What, Why, How?</title><link>/blog/automated-tests-what-why-how/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/automated-tests-what-why-how/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In recent years, automated testing has gained significant traction as a software development best practice. But not everyone&amp;rsquo;s sold or fully understands where to begin in developing such tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some teams fear test-writing may impact velocity. Some believe an ill-designed, legacy codebase makes such tests impossible. Others don&amp;rsquo;t fully grasp the benefits. And others simply don&amp;rsquo;t know where to begin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m frequently asked about automated testing — managers, product owners, UX designers, junior developers, and the uninitiated want to know: Why write tests? Where can I learn more? How do I get started?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>