<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>bash on Mike Ball</title><link>http://mikeball.info/tags/bash/</link><description>Recent content in bash on Mike Ball</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://mikeball.info/tags/bash/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Basic Command Line Tools</title><link>http://mikeball.info/blog/basic-command-line-tools/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mikeball.info/blog/basic-command-line-tools/</guid><description>A co-worker expressed interest in learning more Unix command line operations. This collection seeks to supplement his basic knowledge with some additional tips and tools.
Searching Source Code ack can be downloaded at betterthangrep.com and is a great, free tool for searching a project’s source code. Usage: ack string will return the relative paths to all the files containing the matched string, the line on which the string is found with the match highlighted, and the line number on which the match lives, all while ignoring those files contained within .</description></item><item><title>Simplified Find/Replace from the Command Line</title><link>http://mikeball.info/blog/simplified-find/replace-from-the-command-line/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mikeball.info/blog/simplified-find/replace-from-the-command-line/</guid><description>I recently needed to change all instances of the text /layout/ to /layout_xds/ in a large collection of css files housed throughout multiple levels of subdirectories.
To deal with the problem, I created a bash function to serve as a shortcut wrapping my usage of grep, sed, and uniq. Note that I’m using Mac OS X 10.6.6.
function rep() { for i in `grep -R --exclude=&amp;#34;*.svn*&amp;#34; &amp;#34;$1&amp;#34; * | sed s/:.</description></item><item><title>How to Exclude Files from SVN Commits</title><link>http://mikeball.info/blog/how-to-exclude-files-from-svn-commits/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mikeball.info/blog/how-to-exclude-files-from-svn-commits/</guid><description>In Subversion, svn commit will commit all edited files to the central repository. In the event that I want to selectively commit only a few of my edited files, it&amp;rsquo;s necessary to specify the full path to each file with svn commit /full/path/to/filename1 /full/path/to/filename2 /full/path/to/filename3. This can be time-consuming. Plus, it&amp;rsquo;s often easier to selectively exclude files from a given commit, but Subversion doesn&amp;rsquo;t offer this feature.
The solution I made a bash function that provides a quick way to include/exclude files from an svn commit.</description></item></channel></rss>