<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rails on Mike Ball</title><link>/tags/rails/</link><description>Recent content in Rails on Mike Ball</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/rails/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Secure Session Cookie in Rails over HTTPS</title><link>/blog/secure-session-cookie-in-rails-over-https/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/secure-session-cookie-in-rails-over-https/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The secure flag can be set by an application server when sending a cookie within an HTTP response. By setting the secure flag, an HTTP client — such as a web browser — prevents cookie transmission unless the response is securely encrypted over HTTPS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, many web applications redirect &lt;code&gt;http://&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;https://&lt;/code&gt;, and many Ruby on Rails applications are fronted by a web server such as Ngnix or Apache. Often, &lt;code&gt;HTTPS&lt;/code&gt; is terminated at the Nginx/Apache layer. Given such an architecture, consider the following problematic behavior through which a Ruby on Rails session cookie could be transmitted insecurely in clear text:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>TimesGrapher</title><link>/projects/timesgrapher/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/timesgrapher/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;TimesGrapher seeks to shed light on what topics are covered by the New York Times from year-to-year. The simple application leverages the &lt;a href="http://developer.nytimes.com/docs"&gt;New York Times API&lt;/a&gt; to visualize the differences in coverage offered to any two topics in any year between 1981 and 2013, in effect providing insight on the year-to-year relevancy of current events, as well as arguable editorial bias.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application is built with &lt;a href="http://rubyonrails.org"&gt;Rails&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://backbonejs.org"&gt;Backbone.js&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TimesGrapher was built as a hobby project; it is not affiliated with the New York Times.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>