<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>git on Mike Ball</title><link>/tags/git/</link><description>Recent content in git on Mike Ball</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Committing Via the Concourse Git Resource</title><link>/blog/committing-via-the-concourse-git-resource/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/committing-via-the-concourse-git-resource/</guid><description>A Concourse resource is any entity that can be checked for new versions, fetched at a specific version, and/or pushed up to idempotently create new versions. Concourse&amp;rsquo;s built-in git-resource is a Concourse resource for working with git repositories.
Pulling down a git repository for use in a pipeline job using the git-resource is fairly straight forward:
resources: - name: my-repo type: git source: branch: master uri: https://github.com/my-org/my-repo.git uername: git password: ((github-access-token)) jobs: - name: git-log plan: - get: my-repo - task: show-log config: inputs: - name: my-repo platform: linux image_resource: type: registry-image source: repository: node tag: 6.</description></item><item><title>Collecting Basic Team and Sprint Metrics with Git</title><link>/blog/collecting-basic-team-and-sprint-metrics-with-git/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/collecting-basic-team-and-sprint-metrics-with-git/</guid><description>Per recent co-worker interest in metrics surrounding team performance, the following offer a few simple techniques for extracting team-health-oriented metrics from a git repository. Note that these are just a few basic solutions which require minimal tooling. Many alternative and more-developed solutions exist too.
##View the Total Number of Commits Per Developer within the Codebase
git shortlog -sne View the Total Number of Commits Per Developer Within a Sprint This example assumes that the sprint began on July 1st and ended July 14th.</description></item><item><title>How to Contribute to a Project on GitHub</title><link>/blog/how-to-contribute-to-a-project-on-github/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/how-to-contribute-to-a-project-on-github/</guid><description>A quick how-to in contributing to an open source project hosted on GitHub. These instructions assume you&amp;rsquo;ve already created a GitHub account and properly set up your machine. For more details, GitHub also publishes similar instructions.
Set Up Your Repository Fork a project by visiting its URL on GitHub and clicking the &amp;ldquo;Fork&amp;rdquo; button
Clone your fork to your local machine:
git clone git@github.com:yourUsername/project-name.git Assign the original repository to a remote called &amp;ldquo;upstream&amp;rdquo; to retrieve updates from the original repository you forked:</description></item></channel></rss>