<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>notes on Mike Ball</title><link>/tags/notes/</link><description>Recent content in notes on Mike Ball</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setting Up Postgres on Mac OSX with Homebrew</title><link>/blog/setting-up-postgres-on-mac-osx-with-homebrew/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/setting-up-postgres-on-mac-osx-with-homebrew/</guid><description>I ran into some challenges installing postgres via homebrew. I attempted to follow these instruction, as is advised by the postgres website but ran into further problems. The following steps outline how I was able to finally work around the problems. Note that I&amp;rsquo;m using Mac OSX 10.6.8.
Uninstall old versions of postgres:
brew rm postgresql --force Update homebrew:
brew update Install postgres:
brew install postgresql Make a postgres directory:</description></item><item><title>Basic Command Line Tools</title><link>/blog/basic-command-line-tools/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/basic-command-line-tools/</guid><description>A co-worker expressed interest in learning more Unix command line operations. This collection seeks to supplement his basic knowledge with some additional tips and tools.
Searching Source Code ack can be downloaded at betterthangrep.com and is a great, free tool for searching a project’s source code. Usage: ack string will return the relative paths to all the files containing the matched string, the line on which the string is found with the match highlighted, and the line number on which the match lives, all while ignoring those files contained within .</description></item><item><title>CSS3: An All-CSS, Image-less Play Button</title><link>/blog/css3-an-all-css-image-less-play-button/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/css3-an-all-css-image-less-play-button/</guid><description>The HTML &amp;lt;a class=&amp;#34;thumb&amp;#34; href=&amp;#34;/some-url&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;#34;some-image.jpg&amp;#34; alt=&amp;#34;Image&amp;#34; /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;b class=&amp;#34;play&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;i class=&amp;#34;wave&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; &amp;lt;i class=&amp;#34;arrow&amp;#34;&amp;gt;Play now&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; The CSS /* the anchor tag containing everything */ a.thumb { position:relative; width:300px; height:225px; display:block; } /* the black box */ b.play { display:block; position:absolute; width:80px; height:75px; bottom:0; right:0; background:#1a1a1a; text-indent:-5000px; overflow:hidden; } /* the arrow&amp;#39;s container */ i.</description></item><item><title>How to Make Testable Private Methods in JavaScript</title><link>/blog/how-to-make-testable-private-methods-in-javascript/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/how-to-make-testable-private-methods-in-javascript/</guid><description>Problem: how to write unit tests for private functions?
As my co-worker Trevor suggests in more detail, one solution is to create a class with 3 internal objects:
settings: this object houses configuration options, such as a debug option private: this object houses private functions public: this object houses all public functions Then, in writing unit tests, a developer can instantiate the class by passing {debug: true} to adjust the class&amp;rsquo;s settings such that the private and public objects are merged, in effect exposing the previously private functions housed in the private object.</description></item><item><title>JavaScript Design Patterns</title><link>/blog/javascript-design-patterns/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/javascript-design-patterns/</guid><description>Addy Osmani offers Essential JavaScript &amp;amp; jQuery Design Patterns For Beginners as a free guide to some solutions &amp;ldquo;that can be applied to commonly occurring problems&amp;rdquo; throughout JavaScript. Here are a few of my notes on Osmani’s book, mostly for my own reference:
The Creational Pattern used in creating objects within in application define a class and instantiate it later when you need it var newObject = new MyClass(); The Constructor Function used to create specific types of objects native constructors in JavaScript include Array and Object constructor functions often capitalized to distinguish them from normal functions function Car(model, year, miles){ this.</description></item><item><title>Simplified Find/Replace from the Command Line</title><link>/blog/simplified-find/replace-from-the-command-line/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/simplified-find/replace-from-the-command-line/</guid><description>I recently needed to change all instances of the text /layout/ to /layout_xds/ in a large collection of css files housed throughout multiple levels of subdirectories.
To deal with the problem, I created a bash function to serve as a shortcut wrapping my usage of grep, sed, and uniq. Note that I’m using Mac OS X 10.6.6.
function rep() { for i in `grep -R --exclude=&amp;#34;*.svn*&amp;#34; &amp;#34;$1&amp;#34; * | sed s/:.</description></item><item><title>How to Exclude Files from SVN Commits</title><link>/blog/how-to-exclude-files-from-svn-commits/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/how-to-exclude-files-from-svn-commits/</guid><description>In Subversion, svn commit will commit all edited files to the central repository. In the event that I want to selectively commit only a few of my edited files, it&amp;rsquo;s necessary to specify the full path to each file with svn commit /full/path/to/filename1 /full/path/to/filename2 /full/path/to/filename3. This can be time-consuming. Plus, it&amp;rsquo;s often easier to selectively exclude files from a given commit, but Subversion doesn&amp;rsquo;t offer this feature.
The solution I made a bash function that provides a quick way to include/exclude files from an svn commit.</description></item><item><title>Basic Overview of the Surround Plugin for Vim</title><link>/blog/basic-overview-of-the-surround-plugin-for-vim/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/basic-overview-of-the-surround-plugin-for-vim/</guid><description>Surround is a useful Vim plugin when hand-editing HTML or XML. The plugin can be downloaded via Github or the Vim website and installed by copying the /plugin/surround.vim file to your ~/.vim/plugin/ directory. A few of its basic commands are as follows. Note that each command is entered from within the text to be surrounded:
Adding Surroundings Generally, the cs or ys commands can be used to add surroundings.
Add Surrounding &amp;lt;tag&amp;gt; or Puncation to Word:</description></item></channel></rss>