<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>nicar on Mike Ball</title><link>http://mikeball.info/tags/nicar/</link><description>Recent content in nicar on Mike Ball</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://mikeball.info/tags/nicar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Nicar 2013 Conference</title><link>http://mikeball.info/blog/nicar-2013-conference/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mikeball.info/blog/nicar-2013-conference/</guid><description>On February 27 – March 2, I attended NICAR 2013 in Louisville, Kentucky. My attendance was generously funded through a Temple University Center for Public Interest Journalism sponsorship.
What is NICAR? NICAR is the National Institute for Computer-Assisted Reporting, a program of Investigative Reporters and Editors, Inc. and the Missouri School of Journalism. In the institute’s own words, “NICAR has trained thousands of journalists in the practical skills of finding, prying loose and analyzing electronic information.</description></item><item><title>Using Google Spreadsheets and Tabletop.js as a Web Application Back-end</title><link>http://mikeball.info/blog/using-google-spreadsheets-and-tabletop.js-as-a-web-application-back-end/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mikeball.info/blog/using-google-spreadsheets-and-tabletop.js-as-a-web-application-back-end/</guid><description>At NICAR 2013, Tasneem Raja spoke on Smarter interactive Web projects with Google Spreadsheets and Tabletop.js. Tasneem is Mother Jones‘s Interactive Editor; she outlined how Mother Jones uses Google Spreadsheets to power some of its interactive features.
Beyond serving as a simple, easy-to-maintain datastore and CMS, Google Spreadsheets — used in concert with Tabletop.js — allows for the creation of dynamic web content in absence of server-side processing, in effect empowering a highly scalable and simple architecture.</description></item></channel></rss>