<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cd on Mike Ball</title><link>/tags/cd/</link><description>Recent content in Cd on Mike Ball</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/cd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to Make a Concourse Resource Type</title><link>/blog/how-to-make-a-concourse-resource-type/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/how-to-make-a-concourse-resource-type/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My notes and thoughts on Concourse resource types and when and how to build and test your own resource types&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="context-and-background"&gt;Context and background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Resources&lt;/em&gt; are a core concept in &lt;a href="https://concourse-ci.org"&gt;Concourse&lt;/a&gt; CI/CD pipelines. A &lt;a href="https://concourse-ci.org/resources.html"&gt;resource&lt;/a&gt; is any entity that Concourse can check for new versions, fetch at a specific version, and/or push up changes to idempotently create new versions. In this sense, a resource &amp;ldquo;version&amp;rdquo; is a specific form of a resource that differs from earlier forms, such as a particular commit on a git repository or a particular build artifact object in an AWS S3 bucket. This may sound vague, but it&amp;rsquo;s an arguably compelling feature. Because Concourse&amp;rsquo;s notion of resources offers users a generic way to extend Concourse functionality &amp;ndash; and because Concourse supports the use of custom &lt;a href="https://concourse-ci.org/implementing-resource-types.html"&gt;resource-type implementations&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; resources serve as a useful tool in building Concourse CI/CD pipelines. Pipeline authors can leverage Concourse&amp;rsquo;s built-in resource types, use community-maintained resource types, or create new functionality through their own, custom resource types. And each implementation &amp;ndash; whether it&amp;rsquo;s a built-in resource type, a community-maintained resource type, or a custom, in-house resource type &amp;ndash; is itself packaged and versioned software with its own build/test/release CI/CD lifecycle. In this sense, resource types emerge as an interesting model through which the the units of CI/CD pipeline functionality can be maintained and distributed as first class software projects, and not just ad hoc scripts and untested glue code, as has been historically common.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>