<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>iac on Mike Ball</title><link>/tags/iac/</link><description>Recent content in iac on Mike Ball</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/iac/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Terraform Patterns: the wrapper module</title><link>/blog/terraform-patterns-the-wrapper-module/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/terraform-patterns-the-wrapper-module/</guid><description>Problem Internal to your organization, you want to provide engineers simplified, higher level abstractions for managing AWS resources via Terraform child modules. You could build such modules in-house, but you&amp;rsquo;re wary of the required level of effort and resulting maintenance burden, especially considering the rich ecosystem of well-regarded community-maintained open source modules. However, you&amp;rsquo;d also like to impose some specific governance constraints and a simplified interfaces, restricting each module&amp;rsquo;s use to blessed patterns.</description></item><item><title>Scalable Terraform Patterns: Reuse and Repeatability</title><link>/blog/scalable-terraform-patterns-reuse-and-repeatability/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/scalable-terraform-patterns-reuse-and-repeatability/</guid><description>Child modules: Generic, composable &amp;ldquo;recipes&amp;rdquo; Terraform child modules offer a mechanism for abstracting, packaging, and re-using common Terraform resource configurations across multiple distinct Terraform projects. Child modules expose a simple interface to a more complex underlying configuration, similar to a programming language library or class; they&amp;rsquo;re generic abstractions of opinionated Terraform &amp;ldquo;recipes:&amp;rdquo;
graph LR; A[TF project 1]-->|apply|cloud-provider[cloud provider]; B[TF project 2]-->|apply|cloud-provider; C[TF project 3]-->|apply|cloud-provider; D[TF project 4]-->|apply|cloud-provider; E[TF module]-->A E-->B E-->C E-->D Overview:</description></item><item><title>Scalable Terraform patterns: compound workspace names</title><link>/blog/scalable-terraform-patterns-compound-workspace-names/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/scalable-terraform-patterns-compound-workspace-names/</guid><description>Problem statement As my colleague Brian Tajuddin posits in his rule of never just one:
Writing software these days involves asking the question &amp;ldquo;How many?&amp;rdquo; over and over again. There is one answer that&amp;rsquo;s always wrong.
So, here we are: you need to create and manage similar cloud infrastructure across many different AWS account/region combinations serving different logical environments, such as dev, staging, prod, etc.
For the most part, each environment should be the same as the others, infrastructure-wise.</description></item><item><title>Automated Terraform Plan Analysis With Terratest</title><link>/blog/automated-terraform-plan-analysis-with-terratest/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/automated-terraform-plan-analysis-with-terratest/</guid><description>How can terratest be used to automate Terraform plan analysis?
Problem You want to automate Terraform plan analysis in CI/CD, offsetting some of the manual toil associated with plan assessment. Tools like OPA offer policy-as-code solutions, but your team prefers to write Go.
Solution Usually, terratest is leveraged as a tool for authoring Terraform end-to-end tests that make post-terraform apply assertions on the correctness of the resulting infrastructure.
However, terratest can also be used to programmatically analyze Terraform plan output, effectively offering a Go-based alternative to tools like OPA and similar policy-as-code tools.</description></item></channel></rss>