<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ci on Mike Ball</title><link>/tags/ci/</link><description>Recent content in ci on Mike Ball</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/ci/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to Make a Concourse Resource Type</title><link>/blog/how-to-make-a-concourse-resource-type/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/how-to-make-a-concourse-resource-type/</guid><description>My notes and thoughts on Concourse resource types and when and how to build and test your own resource types.
Context and background Resources are a core concept in Concourse CI/CD pipelines. A resource is any entity that Concourse can check for new versions, fetch at a specific version, and/or push up changes to idempotently create new versions. In this sense, a resource &amp;ldquo;version&amp;rdquo; is a specific form of a resource that differs from earlier forms, such as a particular commit on a git repository or a particular build artifact object in an AWS S3 bucket.</description></item><item><title>How to Test Google Polymer elements on Travis CI</title><link>/blog/how-to-test-google-polymer-elements-on-travis-ci/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/how-to-test-google-polymer-elements-on-travis-ci/</guid><description>Problem: how do you design a cloud-based continuous integration pipeline if your automated application tests relies on technology that requires a GUI, or an actual web browser? Google Polymer heavily leverages Shadow DOM, a feature that&amp;rsquo;s not currently supported in headless JavaScript environments like PhantomJS. My polymer-testing-box demonstrate how to run such tests via Xvfb on a headless Ubuntu VM. Can this technique be used on Travis CI?
Travis CI supports Xvfb and Firefox.</description></item></channel></rss>