<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>open source on Mike Ball</title><link>/tags/open-source/</link><description>Recent content in open source on Mike Ball</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/open-source/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to Contribute to a Project on GitHub</title><link>/blog/how-to-contribute-to-a-project-on-github/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/how-to-contribute-to-a-project-on-github/</guid><description>A quick how-to in contributing to an open source project hosted on GitHub. These instructions assume you&amp;rsquo;ve already created a GitHub account and properly set up your machine. For more details, GitHub also publishes similar instructions.
Set Up Your Repository Fork a project by visiting its URL on GitHub and clicking the &amp;ldquo;Fork&amp;rdquo; button
Clone your fork to your local machine:
git clone git@github.com:yourUsername/project-name.git Assign the original repository to a remote called &amp;ldquo;upstream&amp;rdquo; to retrieve updates from the original repository you forked:</description></item><item><title>Quiet Logger: HTML5 WordPress Theme</title><link>/blog/quiet-logger-html5-wordpress-theme/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/quiet-logger-html5-wordpress-theme/</guid><description>Given increasing enthusiasm for HTML5, as well as an interest in light-weight Wordpress themes, I created Quiet Logger, a minimal WordPress theme typeset in Baskerville and coded with HTML5.
Features Semantically sound and valid HTML5 Minimal, clean, and valid CSS 2.1 HTML5 support to versions of Internet Explorer prior to IE 9 provided via Remy Sharp’s HTML5 Shiv A minimal, typographically strong design based on Baskerville Free and licensed under GPL The source code can be forked on GitHub.</description></item><item><title>OurPhiladelphia.org Launched</title><link>/blog/ourphiladelphia.org-launched/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/ourphiladelphia.org-launched/</guid><description>Last month, Gabriel Farrell, Cecily Anderson, and I launched OurPhiladelphia.org for our client, Common Cause, a nonprofit, nonpartisan citizen’s lobbying organization working to promote open, honest, and accountable government. While we plan to enhance and grow its functionality in the future, we hope this initial iteration of the site proves useful in helping Philadelphians access information about local politics. Our goal is to help create an open, honest, and accountable local government that serves the public interest.</description></item></channel></rss>