<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Polymer on Mike Ball</title><link>/tags/polymer/</link><description>Recent content in Polymer on Mike Ball</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/polymer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to Test Google Polymer elements on Travis CI</title><link>/blog/how-to-test-google-polymer-elements-on-travis-ci/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/how-to-test-google-polymer-elements-on-travis-ci/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Problem: how do you design a cloud-based continuous integration pipeline if your automated application tests relies on technology that requires a GUI, or an actual web browser? &lt;a href="https://www.polymer-project.org"&gt;Google Polymer&lt;/a&gt; heavily leverages &lt;a href="https://w3c.github.io/webcomponents/spec/shadow/"&gt;Shadow DOM&lt;/a&gt;, a feature that&amp;rsquo;s not currently supported in headless JavaScript environments like &lt;a href="http://phantomjs.org/"&gt;PhantomJS&lt;/a&gt;. My &lt;a href="http://github.com/mdb/polymer-testing-box"&gt;polymer-testing-box&lt;/a&gt; demonstrate how to run such tests via &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Xvfb"&gt;Xvfb&lt;/a&gt; on a headless Ubuntu VM. Can this technique be used on &lt;a href="http://travis-ci.org"&gt;Travis CI&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Travis CI supports Xvfb and Firefox. Travis offers &lt;a href="http://docs.travis-ci.com/user/gui-and-headless-browsers/"&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; on leveraging these technologies in its CI environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>JSConf 2015: Headless Testing Against Real Web Browsers</title><link>/blog/jsconf-2015-headless-testing-against-real-web-browsers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/jsconf-2015-headless-testing-against-real-web-browsers/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I spoke at &lt;a href="http://2015.jsconf.us"&gt;JSConf 2015&lt;/a&gt; about how to test Google Polymer web components against real web browsers in a headless Linux using Xvfb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My talk offered background on my philosophy, why some software requires tests be run against a real GUI, and also covered a basic introduction to Xvfb, or X Virtual Frame Buffer. I also demo&amp;rsquo;d &lt;a href="http://github.com/mdb/polymer-testing-box"&gt;polymer-testing-box&lt;/a&gt;, a basic reference implementation illustrating how to provision an Ubuntu VM with all the prerequisites necessary to headlessly run Google Polymer web-component-tester tests against Chrome and Firefox.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>