<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>wordpress on Mike Ball</title><link>http://mikeball.info/tags/wordpress/</link><description>Recent content in wordpress on Mike Ball</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://mikeball.info/tags/wordpress/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>wp2middleman</title><link>http://mikeball.info/projects/wp2middleman/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mikeball.info/projects/wp2middleman/</guid><description>wp2middleman is a Ruby gem that migrates the Wordpress posts in a Wordpress XML export file to middleman-style markdown files.
wp2middleman provides a wp2mm commandline executable, as well as a WP2Middleman module.
View source and documentation on Github »</description></item><item><title>Deploying Wordpress to Pagodabox</title><link>http://mikeball.info/blog/deploying-wordpress-to-pagodabox/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mikeball.info/blog/deploying-wordpress-to-pagodabox/</guid><description>Services such as Heroku provide cloud deployment options for Rails, Sinatra, Django, and Node.js applications, but what about Wordpress? Pagodabox seems promising. Here&amp;rsquo;s how to set up a Wordpress Pagodabox deployment workflow.
Note that these instructions are purposefully verbose in an effort to help those for whom such a workflow may be new and intimidating. Also note that these instructions assume you&amp;rsquo;re using a Mac.
Set up a local instance of Wordpress using MAMP There&amp;rsquo;s probably a fun way to do this with Vagrant, but MAMP will serve our purposes here.</description></item><item><title>Quiet Logger: HTML5 WordPress Theme</title><link>http://mikeball.info/blog/quiet-logger-html5-wordpress-theme/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mikeball.info/blog/quiet-logger-html5-wordpress-theme/</guid><description>Given increasing enthusiasm for HTML5, as well as an interest in light-weight Wordpress themes, I created Quiet Logger, a minimal WordPress theme typeset in Baskerville and coded with HTML5.
Features Semantically sound and valid HTML5 Minimal, clean, and valid CSS 2.1 HTML5 support to versions of Internet Explorer prior to IE 9 provided via Remy Sharp’s HTML5 Shiv A minimal, typographically strong design based on Baskerville Free and licensed under GPL The source code can be forked on GitHub.</description></item><item><title>Taylor &amp; Juliette</title><link>http://mikeball.info/projects/taylor-juliette/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mikeball.info/projects/taylor-juliette/</guid><description>I created a simple brochure website and letter-pressed invite for Taylor &amp;amp; Juliette&amp;rsquo;s wedding. The website and invite feature original illustrations, as well as a hand-drawn typeface created for the wedding materials.</description></item></channel></rss>