<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Civic Technology on Mike Ball</title><link>/tags/civic-technology/</link><description>Recent content in Civic Technology on Mike Ball</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/civic-technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Philadelphia Police Advisory Commission Complaint Map</title><link>/projects/philadelphia-police-advisory-commission-complaint-map/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/philadelphia-police-advisory-commission-complaint-map/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;My map of 2009 – 2012 complaints filed with the Philadelphia Police Advisory Commission won first place at the 2013 Barcamp News Innovation Hackathon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The map plots the details surrounding complaints filed with the Police Advisory Commission by citizens against Philadelphia Police Officers. Its data is published by &lt;a href="http://www.opendataphilly.org/opendata/resource/218/philadelphia-police-advisory-commission-complaints"&gt;Open Data Philly&lt;/a&gt; and has been imported to a public &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheet/ccc?key=0Aii0ITjxvJ6fdFlPNHVINHY2dVhfODNsY2JWU0U0NHc&amp;amp;usp=sharing#gid=0"&gt;Google Spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt;. According to Open Data Philly, the data comes directly from the Police Advisory Commission Complaint Database.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Our Philadelphia</title><link>/projects/our-philadelphia/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/our-philadelphia/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I partnered with Gabriel Farrell and Cecily Anderson to design and build &lt;a href="http://ourphiladelphia.org"&gt;ourphiladelphia.org&lt;/a&gt; for Common Cause, a nonprofit, nonpartisan citizen’s lobbying organization working to promote open, honest, and accountable government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Philadelphia is a community website designed to provide information to Philadelphians about the role of money in local politics. The site features an address-based representative search tool, a news publishing platform, RSS feeds, user accounts and profiles, as well as an extensive database of local campaign donor information. The project was made possible by the Samuel S. Fels Fund.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>