<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>platform engineering on Mike Ball</title><link>/tags/platform-engineering/</link><description>Recent content in platform engineering on Mike Ball</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/platform-engineering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What is the Kubernetes Operator Pattern?</title><link>/blog/what-is-the-kubernetes-operator-pattern/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/what-is-the-kubernetes-operator-pattern/</guid><description>An overview of the Kubernetes operator pattern and the use of custom resources and custom controllers in extending Kubernetes functionality.
What? Broadly speaking, Kubernetes operators seek to abstract, codify, and automate operational tasks beyond what out-of-the-box Kubernetes itself provides.
As summarized in the CNCF Operator Whitepaper:
In Kubernetes, an operator provides intelligent, dynamic management capabilities by extending the functionality of the API.
These operator components allow for the automation of common processes as well as reactive applications that can continually adapt to their environment.</description></item><item><title>Advanced Terraform Logic</title><link>/blog/advanced-terraform-logic/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/advanced-terraform-logic/</guid><description>Critics argue Terraform is limiting and doesn&amp;rsquo;t adequately enable the expression of complex logic. While imperfect, Terraform does indeed often accommodate moderately complex logic. As a reference example, the following illustrates how Terraform constructs such as for_each, for/in, if, try, various functions, and custom local data structures can be used to successfully satisfy a relatively logic-intensive use case.
As a bonus, the reference example also teases some broader techniques for automating platform engineering across an organization.</description></item></channel></rss>